<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ubuntu on clburlison</title>
    <link>https://clburlison.com/tags/ubuntu/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ubuntu on clburlison</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-EN</language>
    <managingEditor>clburlison@gmail.com (Clayton Burlison)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>clburlison@gmail.com (Clayton Burlison)</webMaster>
    <copyright>(c) 2014 - 2017 Clayton Burlison</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 10:21:13 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://clburlison.com/tags/ubuntu/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Chef Grocery Delivery Setup</title>
      <link>https://clburlison.com/chef-grocery-delivery-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 10:21:13 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>clburlison@gmail.com (Clayton Burlison)</author>
      <guid>https://clburlison.com/chef-grocery-delivery-setup/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Grocery Delivery (GD) is a ruby gem that helps keep cookbooks, roles, and data bags in sync between a source control repo and your chef server. This allows administrators to keep their entire chef code in source control with continuous integration, peer reviews, and any other checks they can think of. Once the code has been checked and merged into the master branch the grocery-delivery binary takes the place of knife upload.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setup Munkireport on Ubuntu 14.04 - Part 3</title>
      <link>https://clburlison.com/munkirepo-guide-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>clburlison@gmail.com (Clayton Burlison)</author>
      <guid>https://clburlison.com/munkirepo-guide-part-3/</guid>
      <description>Ubuntu 16.04/ PHP 7: Lucas Hall has created an updated guide based off of this one that uses Ubuntu 16.04 with PHP 7, which can be viewed here.
 Intro Welcome to the third part in our munki server setup series. In this section, we will download and configure Munkireport-php on our munki server.
Before we get to far you might want to head over to Part 1 - Setting up the munki repo or Part 2 - Setting up mandrill.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setup Mandrill on Ubuntu 14.04 - Part 2</title>
      <link>https://clburlison.com/munkirepo-guide-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>clburlison@gmail.com (Clayton Burlison)</author>
      <guid>https://clburlison.com/munkirepo-guide-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Update: This article should only be used for reference at this time. Mandrill has been great for many years but no longer has an active maintainer. Please use MunkiWebAdmin 2 (mwa2) from github.com/munki/mwa2 instead.
 Intro This is Part 2 of a series on setting up a munki server on Ubuntu 14.04. Read Part 1 here. This section goes over setting up Mandrill so we can edit our repo metadata files, modify manifests, and assign new software to our fleet using a web browser.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setup a Munki repo on Ubuntu 14.04 - Part 1</title>
      <link>https://clburlison.com/munkirepo-guide-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>clburlison@gmail.com (Clayton Burlison)</author>
      <guid>https://clburlison.com/munkirepo-guide-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Intro As you might have guessed from my previous post, I am trying to standardize at work. Part of this was to move many core OS X services away from OS X Server and towards Ubuntu. This will allow us to use our existing virtualization infrastructure. After reposado the next big service was our munki repo.
Munki is a very powerful open source tool for patch management and software updates for OS X clients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setup Reposado &#43; Margarita on Ubuntu 14.04</title>
      <link>https://clburlison.com/reposado-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>clburlison@gmail.com (Clayton Burlison)</author>
      <guid>https://clburlison.com/reposado-guide/</guid>
      <description>Intro Why on earth are you creating another guide? Why not use Puppet or Docker? Well the short answer is I could not find anything that covered all the criteria that I needed. I might go back later and puppetize this or use docker but needed a working solution. Plus the first step to automating something is to document how to do it manually, so below is the process to get Reposado and Margarita with Authorization (optional) setup on a clean install of Ubuntu 14.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>