<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Personal on clburlison</title>
    <link>https://clburlison.com/categories/personal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Personal on clburlison</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-EN</language>
    <managingEditor>clburlison@gmail.com (Clayton Burlison)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>clburlison@gmail.com (Clayton Burlison)</webMaster>
    <copyright>(c) 2014 - 2017 Clayton Burlison</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://clburlison.com/categories/personal/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Oracle on Omega at UTA</title>
      <link>https://clburlison.com/oracle-on-omega-at-uta/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>clburlison@gmail.com (Clayton Burlison)</author>
      <guid>https://clburlison.com/oracle-on-omega-at-uta/</guid>
      <description>Intro The University of Texas at Arlington (UTA) has some articles that are quite outdated regarding using their Oracle database server. On top of that no information is given to users that have Macintosh computers. If you happen to be taking an Information System class like Database Management Systems (INSY 3304) then good luck when it comes to remotely connecting to the Oracle server. To make-up for the lack of documentation I am creating the following guide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java, CoreOS, Docker, &amp; More</title>
      <link>https://clburlison.com/java-coreos-docker-and-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>clburlison@gmail.com (Clayton Burlison)</author>
      <guid>https://clburlison.com/java-coreos-docker-and-more/</guid>
      <description>Quick Update Firstly, the new semester has started up and my previous goal of one post per month might become a little more difficult to keep up with. For that reason I will be making this post mostly personal opinions and ideas rather than technical writing.
It has certainly been a busy start to this school year getting multiple labs ready, updating computers, installing new software, and plenty of other daily tasks that are quite difficult to stay on top of.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I love my job?</title>
      <link>https://clburlison.com/why-i-love-my-job/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>clburlison@gmail.com (Clayton Burlison)</author>
      <guid>https://clburlison.com/why-i-love-my-job/</guid>
      <description>I get to be everyone&amp;rsquo;s white knight
Technology Superhero
Or my personal favorite wizard
All funny pictures aside, being in the information technology field is a perfect fit for me. When people ask for help I get to take personal satisfaction in helping them. Very few times do I have to send the task to another tech. Sometimes this turns into a mini-adventure to learn how to fix the problem. Plus, my end users have a name and face to the person helping.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>