<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tech on clburlison</title>
    <link>https://clburlison.com/categories/tech/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tech on clburlison</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-EN</language>
    <managingEditor>clburlison@gmail.com (Clayton Burlison)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>clburlison@gmail.com (Clayton Burlison)</webMaster>
    <copyright>(c) 2014 - 2017 Clayton Burlison</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://clburlison.com/categories/tech/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Office 2016 admin candy</title>
      <link>https://clburlison.com/office-2016-admin-candy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>clburlison@gmail.com (Clayton Burlison)</author>
      <guid>https://clburlison.com/office-2016-admin-candy/</guid>
      <description>Office 2016 has had a few updates since my last post on the topic however most of these simply don&amp;rsquo;t apply to me as an admin of the mac platform. Many of these updates have been bug and feature related which is great&amp;hellip;I just do not see them as I am not a user. Honestly, since I finished college in December I have not used a Microsoft product on my mac except for Microsoft Remote Desktop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10.12.4 locationd</title>
      <link>https://clburlison.com/10.12.4-locationd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 09:12:44 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>clburlison@gmail.com (Clayton Burlison)</author>
      <guid>https://clburlison.com/10.12.4-locationd/</guid>
      <description>Update: I made an incorrect assumption regarding SIP and the change with 10.12.4. This post has been corrected. Thanks Patrick Gallagher and Pepijn Bruienne for pointing out the mistake.
 New with 10.12.4, Apple has decided to protect the locationd LaunchDaemon with System Integrity Protection (SIP).
If you are not aware the locationd daemon is used for Location Services. This is the process that drives: FindMyMac, &amp;ldquo;Set time zone automatically using current location&amp;rdquo;, it allows applications to locate your computer, and more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chef Grocery Delivery Setup</title>
      <link>https://clburlison.com/chef-grocery-delivery-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 10:21:13 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>clburlison@gmail.com (Clayton Burlison)</author>
      <guid>https://clburlison.com/chef-grocery-delivery-setup/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Grocery Delivery (GD) is a ruby gem that helps keep cookbooks, roles, and data bags in sync between a source control repo and your chef server. This allows administrators to keep their entire chef code in source control with continuous integration, peer reviews, and any other checks they can think of. Once the code has been checked and merged into the master branch the grocery-delivery binary takes the place of knife upload.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>python2 and tls</title>
      <link>https://clburlison.com/python2-and-tls/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>clburlison@gmail.com (Clayton Burlison)</author>
      <guid>https://clburlison.com/python2-and-tls/</guid>
      <description>For your Friday viewing pleasure I present the following cartoon.
 Credit: https://xkcd.com/356/   Background In case you do not know Apple deprecated the usage of OpenSSL in favor of Common Crypto, back with the release of OS X Lion (10.7) in 2011. On Apple&amp;rsquo;s latest operating system macOS Sierra (10.12) OpenSSL is currently at version &amp;ldquo;0.9.8zh&amp;rdquo; with very little indication that it will get updated. Now this is a specific build that Apple created and it does have a few back-ported fixes however this version doesn&amp;rsquo;t support TLSv1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Xcode Dynamic BundleVersion</title>
      <link>https://clburlison.com/xcode-dynamic-bundleversion/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>clburlison@gmail.com (Clayton Burlison)</author>
      <guid>https://clburlison.com/xcode-dynamic-bundleversion/</guid>
      <description>So lets start with I&amp;rsquo;m not a developer. I won&amp;rsquo;t pretend to be one but I do find development work quite interesting. One thing I&amp;rsquo;m trying to get into is Swift but even the small steps lead me to realize how large the Apple ecosystem is. Cocoa, Swift, Xcode, System frameworks, finding the right documentation, etc. The process of connecting the dots takes a bit of time as you might imagine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zendesk Automation for Mail</title>
      <link>https://clburlison.com/zendesk-automation-for-mail/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>clburlison@gmail.com (Clayton Burlison)</author>
      <guid>https://clburlison.com/zendesk-automation-for-mail/</guid>
      <description>Intro Before I get into the material of this post I want to refer you to an article written last week by Sal Soghoian, click here. The information that he provides regarding user automation is exactly what makes the process described in this post possible.
In case you are not aware, Zendesk is a web-based helpdesk application that is cloud hosted and quite popular. They have an email API that allows agents to create a ticket with a simple email.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AutoWake</title>
      <link>https://clburlison.com/autowake/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>clburlison@gmail.com (Clayton Burlison)</author>
      <guid>https://clburlison.com/autowake/</guid>
      <description>Apple has some pretty nice energy savings options built into macOS. Most of these options are tucked nicely inside of the Energy Saver pane of System Preferences.
The above settings get written to the com.apple.AutoWake preference and looks like:
defaults read /Library/Preferences/SystemConfiguration/com.apple.AutoWake { RepeatingPowerOff = { eventtype = shutdown; time = 1020; weekdays = 127; }; RepeatingPowerOn = { eventtype = wakepoweron; time = 420; weekdays = 31; }; }  Weekdays Some of these values are a bit opaque once they are written to the preferences domain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OPMA 3306 SAP Help</title>
      <link>https://clburlison.com/opma-3306/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>clburlison@gmail.com (Clayton Burlison)</author>
      <guid>https://clburlison.com/opma-3306/</guid>
      <description>Java! Currently, I am taking an Operating Management class which uses an Enterprise Resource Planning (ERP) application. The instructions given to my peers consistents of:
 Download this file Download one of these two other files (no notes on how to use either config file) Open this jar file and a PS note that you need the Java SDK installed  Okay fine I can deal with bad setup instructions&amp;hellip;then I got an error message and gave up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adobe CC Oops</title>
      <link>https://clburlison.com/adobe-cc-oops/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>clburlison@gmail.com (Clayton Burlison)</author>
      <guid>https://clburlison.com/adobe-cc-oops/</guid>
      <description>I ran into the following error earlier this year and have yet to write about it. Adobe has the correct solution in another knowledge base article however the error messages are different. Since the errors looked to be different I never would have attempted the solution until Karl gave me a poke.
Basically I would launch Adobe&amp;rsquo;s Creative Cloud Packager (CCP) tool and nothing would work. Luckily the fix is really simple:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demystify Office 2016 for Mac</title>
      <link>https://clburlison.com/demystify-office2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>clburlison@gmail.com (Clayton Burlison)</author>
      <guid>https://clburlison.com/demystify-office2016/</guid>
      <description>Intro Microsoft Office 2016 for Mac had a rough start for sure. With that being said things have gotten better and quite rapidly. This post will focus on where Office 2016 for Mac currently stands, commonly asked questions, best practices, and solutions for updates.
This post should serve as a overview of the changes to Office 2016 (O2016) for Mac from about November 2015 to Present (January 14th).
Before we can get too far into this post it needs to be noted that none of this would be possible without the hard work and support of the following individuals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hack The Mac 2015</title>
      <link>https://clburlison.com/hack-the-mac-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>clburlison@gmail.com (Clayton Burlison)</author>
      <guid>https://clburlison.com/hack-the-mac-2015/</guid>
      <description>I almost missed Hack the Mac this year but luckily Twitter let me know once it had already started. Since I showed up late, I missed the first project overview and needed to go back to the video on demand to review what was said. While I was watching I thought it might be useful for others if I compiled a short overview with video links.
All three projects were already brought to my attention before the event but here is my take away after watching the event:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slack rsync</title>
      <link>https://clburlison.com/slack-rsync/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>clburlison@gmail.com (Clayton Burlison)</author>
      <guid>https://clburlison.com/slack-rsync/</guid>
      <description>With a little push from @groob, I have created a simple python script that runs a rsync command and sends a summary of the run to Slack. Slack was not created to be a storage vault for server logs however it does great for short sms style messages. If you are using a log collection service like logstash you could extend on this script to include the link to your uploaded log or if an error occurs you could automatically create a helpdesk ticket for you to investigate the issue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iPhone 6S tips</title>
      <link>https://clburlison.com/iphone-6s-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>clburlison@gmail.com (Clayton Burlison)</author>
      <guid>https://clburlison.com/iphone-6s-tips/</guid>
      <description>Many users are upgrading phones in light of the new iPhone Upgrade Program or because they need to have the latest and greatest. With a bigger screen comes the issue of how do I use this phone? It&amp;rsquo;s literally too big for my hand! For that I recommend the following links. I&amp;rsquo;m also including the reachability link because it seems many iPhone 6/plus users don&amp;rsquo;t know about this feature. I can&amp;rsquo;t imagine using one of these phones without the reachability function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Import Logic Pro X Audio Content</title>
      <link>https://clburlison.com/import-logic-pro-x/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>clburlison@gmail.com (Clayton Burlison)</author>
      <guid>https://clburlison.com/import-logic-pro-x/</guid>
      <description>Updated for Logic 10.2.0 - September 18th, 2015
This script has been updated to support Logic Pro 10.2.0. This release included many additional audio libraries for the added Alchemy Plugin. The updated script from Hannes will now download audio content to a &amp;ldquo;__Downloaded Items&amp;rdquo; directory and create hard links to Apple&amp;rsquo;s categories.
 Today I needed to import 60 packages (37 GB) of audio content for Logic Pro X into my Munki repo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Imagr in production</title>
      <link>https://clburlison.com/imagr-in-production/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>clburlison@gmail.com (Clayton Burlison)</author>
      <guid>https://clburlison.com/imagr-in-production/</guid>
      <description>Intro Many have written about Imagr but few have made the claim of dropping their old imaging solution completely. I made the claim in May after extensively testing Imagr with virtual machines however the real test was this week with 90 brand new Macs. That&amp;rsquo;s right the good ol&amp;rsquo; unboxing, labeling, tagging, and prepping. It is the end of the school year and the Audio Video Department was pretty much done with gear, so I made a time lapse of the entire process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuration Management</title>
      <link>https://clburlison.com/configuration-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>clburlison@gmail.com (Clayton Burlison)</author>
      <guid>https://clburlison.com/configuration-management/</guid>
      <description>Intro This is part one in a four part series on using Puppet on OS X. However to understand my move to Puppet I wanted to share my thoughts on Configuration Management (CM) in general.
For the last five months, I have been seriously questioning my deployment/management process. Even with Munki&amp;rsquo;s native support for configuration profiles in v2.2.4, it has always seemed like I was creating extra work for myself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automator is not dead yet</title>
      <link>https://clburlison.com/automator-is-not-dead-yet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>clburlison@gmail.com (Clayton Burlison)</author>
      <guid>https://clburlison.com/automator-is-not-dead-yet/</guid>
      <description>Intro Automator is unique in its ability of creating &amp;ldquo;automation&amp;rdquo; via the usage of a graphical tasked based workflow. Most other tools that I use for automation are command line driven. So what can you do that&amp;rsquo;s so amazing?
 Create applications. No really Automator has the ability to create a .app. Create services. The ability to directly apply changes inside of applications. It is easy! No advanced computer skills are needed, however scripting languages are a great addition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AD Account Change</title>
      <link>https://clburlison.com/adacctchange/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>clburlison@gmail.com (Clayton Burlison)</author>
      <guid>https://clburlison.com/adacctchange/</guid>
      <description>Intro Changing user account logons in a deployed environment can cause some issues. Doing so with OS X clients that are bound to Active Directory can cause even more issues. Below is how I overcame some of the pitfalls of the built-in OS X Active Directory plugin. This article expands on the basic project Readme instructions located here.
Note: The above picture is for reference purposes only. All data has been modified.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shrinking a linux virtual disk</title>
      <link>https://clburlison.com/shrink-linux-vm-disk/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>clburlison@gmail.com (Clayton Burlison)</author>
      <guid>https://clburlison.com/shrink-linux-vm-disk/</guid>
      <description>I have written about shrinking the virtual disk of an OS X Virtual Machine here but recently I needed to shrink a Linux virtual machine. The process is almost identical across all of VMware&amp;rsquo;s products you just have to find the vmware-vdiskmanager tool.
The process In most operating systems removing the files from the disk merely alters file tables so the operating system sees the space as free on the disk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puppet Module desktop picture</title>
      <link>https://clburlison.com/puppet-module-desktoppicture/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>clburlison@gmail.com (Clayton Burlison)</author>
      <guid>https://clburlison.com/puppet-module-desktoppicture/</guid>
      <description>Intro I have been using puppet in one way or another since April of 2014. My first introduction to puppet was boxen but up until recently I have only focused on how puppet can apply to me personally. With this module and a few ideas I have for the future this is going to change the way clients are configured at $work_place.
Now this technically is not my first module it is the first module that I have created the logic and wrote entirely myself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jekyll Pull Requests</title>
      <link>https://clburlison.com/jekyll-pull-requests/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>clburlison@gmail.com (Clayton Burlison)</author>
      <guid>https://clburlison.com/jekyll-pull-requests/</guid>
      <description>Outdated: I am no longer using this process nor is the original author that I was linking to. He has an archive of his post here.
 Github is awesome. Jekyll is awesome. Travis-ci is awesome. Prose.io is awesome. And now&amp;hellip;you can be awesome as well. Open Source is a fantastic but it is not without its drawbacks. One of the biggest drawbacks to using a static website like this site is the lack of an easy way to update posts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fix Munkireport Error Request Too Large</title>
      <link>https://clburlison.com/munkireport-error-fix/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>clburlison@gmail.com (Clayton Burlison)</author>
      <guid>https://clburlison.com/munkireport-error-fix/</guid>
      <description>Intro I use Munkireport-php as my main reporting system at my work but have recently ran into an error when uploading data from client machines. My setup is using nginx to serve the files.
Error message The error message below is what was showing up from a manual munki run with verbose enabled, you can run the command with:
sudo /usr/local/munki/managedsoftwareupdate -v  ... Starting... Running preinstall_script for munkireport... BaseURL is http://munki01.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sign Packages with Luggage</title>
      <link>https://clburlison.com/sign-packages-with-luggage/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>clburlison@gmail.com (Clayton Burlison)</author>
      <guid>https://clburlison.com/sign-packages-with-luggage/</guid>
      <description>Intro Are you an Apple Developer? Most of the Apple Admin Community have developer accounts for the simple reason of gaining access to beta releases earlier than the public. This extra times allows us to test for changes that might affect the environments we support before it ends up in the hands of our users. Up until this point that is the only reason I could justify having a Dev account.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preview files from terminal</title>
      <link>https://clburlison.com/preview-files-from-terminal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>clburlison@gmail.com (Clayton Burlison)</author>
      <guid>https://clburlison.com/preview-files-from-terminal/</guid>
      <description>QuickLook scans file contents before you open those files. Usually this just lets you view a file quickly. But you can also use this same technology from the command line to bring about a change to the Finder without actually opening a file. To access QuickLook from the command line, use qlmanage.
qlmanage -p ~/Desktop/MyTowel42.pdf
&amp;mdash;Charles Edge
 I highly recommend adding an alias to your either your .bashrc or .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setup Munkireport on Ubuntu 14.04 - Part 3</title>
      <link>https://clburlison.com/munkirepo-guide-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>clburlison@gmail.com (Clayton Burlison)</author>
      <guid>https://clburlison.com/munkirepo-guide-part-3/</guid>
      <description>Ubuntu 16.04/ PHP 7: Lucas Hall has created an updated guide based off of this one that uses Ubuntu 16.04 with PHP 7, which can be viewed here.
 Intro Welcome to the third part in our munki server setup series. In this section, we will download and configure Munkireport-php on our munki server.
Before we get to far you might want to head over to Part 1 - Setting up the munki repo or Part 2 - Setting up mandrill.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setup Mandrill on Ubuntu 14.04 - Part 2</title>
      <link>https://clburlison.com/munkirepo-guide-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>clburlison@gmail.com (Clayton Burlison)</author>
      <guid>https://clburlison.com/munkirepo-guide-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Update: This article should only be used for reference at this time. Mandrill has been great for many years but no longer has an active maintainer. Please use MunkiWebAdmin 2 (mwa2) from github.com/munki/mwa2 instead.
 Intro This is Part 2 of a series on setting up a munki server on Ubuntu 14.04. Read Part 1 here. This section goes over setting up Mandrill so we can edit our repo metadata files, modify manifests, and assign new software to our fleet using a web browser.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setup a Munki repo on Ubuntu 14.04 - Part 1</title>
      <link>https://clburlison.com/munkirepo-guide-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>clburlison@gmail.com (Clayton Burlison)</author>
      <guid>https://clburlison.com/munkirepo-guide-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Intro As you might have guessed from my previous post, I am trying to standardize at work. Part of this was to move many core OS X services away from OS X Server and towards Ubuntu. This will allow us to use our existing virtualization infrastructure. After reposado the next big service was our munki repo.
Munki is a very powerful open source tool for patch management and software updates for OS X clients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setup Reposado &#43; Margarita on Ubuntu 14.04</title>
      <link>https://clburlison.com/reposado-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>clburlison@gmail.com (Clayton Burlison)</author>
      <guid>https://clburlison.com/reposado-guide/</guid>
      <description>Intro Why on earth are you creating another guide? Why not use Puppet or Docker? Well the short answer is I could not find anything that covered all the criteria that I needed. I might go back later and puppetize this or use docker but needed a working solution. Plus the first step to automating something is to document how to do it manually, so below is the process to get Reposado and Margarita with Authorization (optional) setup on a clean install of Ubuntu 14.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shellshock</title>
      <link>https://clburlison.com/shellshock/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>clburlison@gmail.com (Clayton Burlison)</author>
      <guid>https://clburlison.com/shellshock/</guid>
      <description>On September 24, 2014, a security vulnerability was publicly announced that affects a large percentage of Internet connected devices. This vulnerability, known as Shellshock, affects the Unix command shell Bash. Bash, the bourne again shell, is one of the most common applications on Unix based systems. Many devices running Mac OS X or Linux are affected by this serious exploit.
It is important to understand that this vulnerability could allow unauthorized access of your computer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java, CoreOS, Docker, &amp; More</title>
      <link>https://clburlison.com/java-coreos-docker-and-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>clburlison@gmail.com (Clayton Burlison)</author>
      <guid>https://clburlison.com/java-coreos-docker-and-more/</guid>
      <description>Quick Update Firstly, the new semester has started up and my previous goal of one post per month might become a little more difficult to keep up with. For that reason I will be making this post mostly personal opinions and ideas rather than technical writing.
It has certainly been a busy start to this school year getting multiple labs ready, updating computers, installing new software, and plenty of other daily tasks that are quite difficult to stay on top of.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vimium</title>
      <link>https://clburlison.com/vimium/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>clburlison@gmail.com (Clayton Burlison)</author>
      <guid>https://clburlison.com/vimium/</guid>
      <description>The Hacker&amp;rsquo;s Browser Plugin A plugin that increases speed and efficiency while browsing the internet? Yes please! I only recently found out about Vimium and wanted to share my thoughts on this plugin.
We all spend too much time on the internet. Reading forums, blogs, facebook, twitter, news, youtube,&amp;hellip;the list goes on and on. Phil Crosby and Ilya Sukhar created Vimium to speed up the navigation of websites. No longer must you use your mouse to click that link, or trackpad to scroll down.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Classroom</title>
      <link>https://clburlison.com/google-classroom/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>clburlison@gmail.com (Clayton Burlison)</author>
      <guid>https://clburlison.com/google-classroom/</guid>
      <description>Chromebooks are pretty popular in Education right now due to their low learning curve, low price, and high usability. They are quite good at simple projects and give more students access to the internet. Now Google wants to remove paper&amp;hellip;
 Hopefully Classroom will help you spend a little less time at the photocopier and a little more time doing what you love—teaching.
 Read more: More Teaching Less Tech-ing</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving to Plain Jekyll</title>
      <link>https://clburlison.com/moving-to-plain-jekyll/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>clburlison@gmail.com (Clayton Burlison)</author>
      <guid>https://clburlison.com/moving-to-plain-jekyll/</guid>
      <description>Moved the blog over from Octopress to a plain Jekyll setup. This allows me to have a bit more control while also removing some of the fluff that was installed by Octopress that I did not use. I am very glad to have found such a great theme created by Michael Rose. I will release another post once I have had a little more time to play around. As of this moment, it is about 10 times faster to generate the website on my laptop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bash if then cheat sheet</title>
      <link>https://clburlison.com/bash-if-then-cheat-sheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>clburlison@gmail.com (Clayton Burlison)</author>
      <guid>https://clburlison.com/bash-if-then-cheat-sheet/</guid>
      <description>I always find myself looking for a good resource when writing if/then statements in bash scripts. It&amp;rsquo;s hard to remember all the combinations when you simply do not use most of them frequently. Below is my personal cheat sheet&amp;hellip;copied here because I was tired of having to look for a good resource.
Examples on usage can be found in the original article.
integer comparison # The following are for number values only.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Converting Audio With Media Encoder</title>
      <link>https://clburlison.com/converting-audio-with-media-encoder/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>clburlison@gmail.com (Clayton Burlison)</author>
      <guid>https://clburlison.com/converting-audio-with-media-encoder/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I received a unique request today from a co-worker of mine. In short, he asked me if I was able to convert an audio clip from a Tascam audio recorder to a lower quality format suitable for our phone distribution system. The real challenge&amp;hellip;was I going to be able to do this with the software currently installed?
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Show Help Desk Information</title>
      <link>https://clburlison.com/show-helpdesk-info/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>clburlison@gmail.com (Clayton Burlison)</author>
      <guid>https://clburlison.com/show-helpdesk-info/</guid>
      <description>Display useful information on your Desktop using Geektool. Make troubleshooting network issues for your end users easier. Find your hostname faster. The amount of useful information is limitless. If you can script it&amp;hellip;you can display it.
 My geektools results.   Introduction Firstly, I take no credit for this valuable resource. All credit should go to Erik Gomez from the munki-dev mailing list. All I have done is modified the script to work in my environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bender</title>
      <link>https://clburlison.com/bender/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>clburlison@gmail.com (Clayton Burlison)</author>
      <guid>https://clburlison.com/bender/</guid>
      <description>Many administrators use OS X Server. In my opinion the server OS has always lacked choices when it comes to backing up the server services data. Until I found Bender&amp;hellip;
 Bender is a utility written by Forget Computers to automate the backup of OS X Server settings to provide easy restoration of services should they become corrupt, and for importing server settings after a migration or server upgrade.
Bender Home Page</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Encrypted DMGs</title>
      <link>https://clburlison.com/encrypted-dmgs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>clburlison@gmail.com (Clayton Burlison)</author>
      <guid>https://clburlison.com/encrypted-dmgs/</guid>
      <description>We all know about file security but how many of our users take the time to properly protect their data? Sure you can make policy but unless someone documents the expectations, reasons, and how to do it, many users will simply ignore policy. How about personal files, we all store data on our computers that we know should be protect but how? Well luckily Apple has a very simple solution to the problem explained above.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Find My Mac</title>
      <link>https://clburlison.com/find-my-mac/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>clburlison@gmail.com (Clayton Burlison)</author>
      <guid>https://clburlison.com/find-my-mac/</guid>
      <description>Under the hood of Find My Mac there are some security details that are not widely published. These details should not concern most consumers however I found them quite interesting.
When a user enables Find My Mac (FMM) on their computer this is a system level change. This means if a user wishes to enable FMM they must be an administrator of the computer. A result of this is that in most environments where students are standard users this feature should never be enabled by accident.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a development munki_repo</title>
      <link>https://clburlison.com/creating-a-development-munki-repo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>clburlison@gmail.com (Clayton Burlison)</author>
      <guid>https://clburlison.com/creating-a-development-munki-repo/</guid>
      <description>Outdated: These instructions are no longer current and are considered deprecated. This document remains for historical reasons only. Faster and easier methods exist for creating development environments.
 I created a vagrant box that allows you create a completely self contained munki_repo for testing purposes. With the usage of PuPHPet the process was quite easy.
This article describes basic usage and setup for the project munki.dev.
Purpose Setting up and maintaining a web server can be a pretty complex job.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Github Two-factor Authentication with SourceTree</title>
      <link>https://clburlison.com/github-two-factor-authentication/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>clburlison@gmail.com (Clayton Burlison)</author>
      <guid>https://clburlison.com/github-two-factor-authentication/</guid>
      <description>I finally got around to setting up two-factor authentication on my Github account. The process went quite smoothly, until I started to play around with SourceTree and I found out that I was unable to push commits to a git repo.
SourceTree error The error message that I was receiving seemed pretty generic at the time. Besides I knew I was typing my Github password correctly, so that could not be the issue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Things learned from boxen</title>
      <link>https://clburlison.com/things-learned-from-boxen/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>clburlison@gmail.com (Clayton Burlison)</author>
      <guid>https://clburlison.com/things-learned-from-boxen/</guid>
      <description>What is boxen? So odds are if you have landed on this page you have probably already heard of boxen. For those who have not heard yet, boxen is an open source project created by the good people at github.com as a way to quickly setup a Macintosh computer. Boxen can also be used as a way to keep certain settings managed between two or more devices. Think for a second, your laptop goes with you everywhere and along with that you have all of your custom shell scripts, shell alias, ssh keys, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enable AirDrop on Ethernet</title>
      <link>https://clburlison.com/enable-airdrop-on-ethernet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>clburlison@gmail.com (Clayton Burlison)</author>
      <guid>https://clburlison.com/enable-airdrop-on-ethernet/</guid>
      <description>A quick post over enabling AirDrop to use an ethernet connection along with the default wireless connection.
 AirDrop helps you share items with others nearby&amp;hellip;a quick way to share files wirelessly between two Macs, without having to connect to an existing network.
&amp;ndash; Apple KB Article
 AirDrop provides a great file-sharing experience and numerous departments at my workplace have grown to love it. The service is good for simple file exchanges without needing to use a files-share.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up octopress</title>
      <link>https://clburlison.com/setting-up-octopress/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>clburlison@gmail.com (Clayton Burlison)</author>
      <guid>https://clburlison.com/setting-up-octopress/</guid>
      <description>Notice: This site is no created using Octopress. I have since moved to a plain Jekyll setup. Content exists mostly for reference and will not be updated in the future.
 Setting up a blog can be a time consuming task. Setting up a blog that is created from static (markdown) files can be much more time consuming. In this post, I list references to most of the custom changes that were made to this site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploying Octopress to Amazon S3</title>
      <link>https://clburlison.com/deploying-octopress-to-amazon-s3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>clburlison@gmail.com (Clayton Burlison)</author>
      <guid>https://clburlison.com/deploying-octopress-to-amazon-s3/</guid>
      <description>Notice: This site is no created using Octopress. I have since moved to a plain Jekyll setup. Content exists mostly for reference and will not be updated in the future.
 This post will go over how I upload my octopress site from my computer to Amazon s3 cloud service using s3cmd.
Firstly, you will need to sign up for an Amazon AWS account if you do not have one already.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up a puppetmaster on Mavericks</title>
      <link>https://clburlison.com/setting-up-a-puppetmaster-on-mavericks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>clburlison@gmail.com (Clayton Burlison)</author>
      <guid>https://clburlison.com/setting-up-a-puppetmaster-on-mavericks/</guid>
      <description>For various reasons I decided to set up my puppetmaster on an OS X install of Mavericks instead of what I would consider the norm, being a linux distro. Here are the results. This documentation is strongly based on the article by Nate Walck on afp548.com.
Notice: I do not use these instructions any longer. The setup of a puppetmaster on OS X Server was just for testing purposes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shrinking the disk image of an OS X VM</title>
      <link>https://clburlison.com/shrinking-the-disk-image-of-an-os-x-vm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>clburlison@gmail.com (Clayton Burlison)</author>
      <guid>https://clburlison.com/shrinking-the-disk-image-of-an-os-x-vm/</guid>
      <description>Reducing the size of a guest OS X Virtual Machines&amp;rsquo;s vmdk file requires a few steps. For a Windows VM&amp;rsquo;s, there is a tool from VMWare with a GUI. Unfortunately, there is not an equivalent tool for the Mac guest VM.
This technique has tested and confirmed on OS X 10.9.2 using VMware Fusion 6.02 though it should work from 10.7 and up. This assumes your guest vm’s disk is not pre-allocated, and the virtual machine does not have any snapshots.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First post</title>
      <link>https://clburlison.com/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>clburlison@gmail.com (Clayton Burlison)</author>
      <guid>https://clburlison.com/first-post/</guid>
      <description>This blog is setup as a personal resource for myself. Eventually, I will grow the information on this blog so that others can gain some educational value.
The site originally was hosted on Amazon&amp;rsquo;s S3 backend with the content being created through Octopress.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>